http://www.thehonestkitchen.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Your privacy and the privacy of all visitors to the TheHonestKitchen.com Web Site (the “Web Site”) are very important to us. In this privacy policy (“Policy”), we explain how and why we collect, use, and disclose your information, including personal information, that we collect through this Site.
For California residents, please see the section at the end of this Notice entitled Important Additional Privacy Information for California Residents (the “California Section”), which discusses the categories and specific pieces of personal information that we collect from California residents, how we use that information, and California residents’ rights with respect to the personal information we collect. If any other section in this Privacy Policy can be read to conflict with the California Section, then the California Section controls with respect to California residents.
Any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. Our Terms of Use are incorporated by reference into this Policy. If you do not agree with this Policy or our Terms of Use, you must stop using our Services.
Notice of information collected
We collect information directly from you, automatically as you use our Web Site, and from other sources. The type of information that we collect about you varies based on your interaction with our Site and services and may include: identifying information (such as your name, email, IP address); purchase history; usage information (about your use our Site); geolocation information; and inferences about you (e.g., based on purchase history). We collect this information as follows:
Information that We Collect Directly From You: We collect identifying information, financial information, demographic information, purchase history/customer records, and other information as described below when you use our Site or otherwise interact with us. In particular, we collect information from you when you take the following actions:
Create an Account: You may create an account on our Site. We will collect your name, email address, and other information that you choose to provide (e.g., whether you have a cat or a dog).
Make a Purchase: When you make a purchase from us, we will collect your name, billing and shipping addresses, email, phone number, payment card information, and items purchased.
Post a True Story: We love hearing about your pets! If you post a true story, we will collect your pet’s breed, health condition, pet’s name and photo, and any other information that you choose to provide to us.
Sign Up for our Newsletter: We collect your email address if you request our newsletter.
Post to our Services or Our Social Media Pages: You may post your photos or other content, such as reviews, to our Services, as indicated, and on our social media pages.
Rewards Program: If you sign up for our rewards program, we collect your name, email, order information, whether you create true story, submit a product or Site review, or refer a friend.
Sign Up for Our Texting Program: We collect your mobile phone number if you choose to participate in our text messaging program .
Participate in a Survey: If you choose to provide feedback, such as participating in a survey, we will collect this information from you, which may include your contact information and your feedback.
Contact Customer Service: We collect information about you when you contact our customer service department, whether by phone, mail, or email. This includes your name, contact number, and scope of your inquiry.
Participate in Promotions: If you participate in a promotion, then we will collect the information that you submit as part of your entry. We may offer promotions in connection with other entities, and, in some cases, our promotions will be governed by additional or different privacy notices; we will notify you at the time of collection if your data will be subject to an additional or different policy.
Information We Collect About You From Other Sources:
Your Friends: We may collect information about you if your friends purchase a gift or product for you or if they refer you to our Site. .
Social Media: If you post information on our social media pages, we may collect the information that you post. We also may obtain information about you through your social media pages that you have made public if you mention us in a post. Our collection of information about you is governed by the social media page and not this policy. We do not typically associate your social media information with the personal information we collect about you.
Internet Service Providers, Operating Systems, Analytics Providers: As stated above, we collect data automatically through your use of our Site and our services. This information may come from internet service providers, operating systems, and analytics providers that provide services on our behalf.
Advertising Networks: We engage (either directly or through a marketing agency) advertising networks to assist us with our targeted advertising. These advertising networks typically do not provide information back to us about you as an individual, but we may learn more broadly about the success of our advertising campaigns through these entities.
Information We Collect Automatically: We automatically collect information about you when you use our services (usage information). The type of information that we collect varies depending on the settings of your web browser or device, but it may include the pages you view on our Site; the date and time you access our Site; how long you use our services; the type of web browser you are using (for example, Firefox or Chrome); the type of device you are using (for example, whether you are using a mobile device); and your Internet Protocol address; device ID; your location information (collected, e.g., through our analytics providers such as Google). Our service providers also may track your behavior through links that you click on our Site. See the section below titled Cookies and Tracking for more information. We do not typically associate this information with the personal information that we collect about you. We collect this information from:
Internet Service Providers, Operating Systems, Analytics Providers: As stated above, we collect data automatically through your use of our Site and our services. This information may come from internet service providers, operating systems, and analytics providers that provide services on our behalf.
Advertising Networks: We engage (either directly or through a marketing agency) advertising networks to assist us with our targeted advertising. These advertising networks typically do not provide information back to us about you as an individual, but we may learn more broadly about the success of our advertising campaigns through these entities.
Our Use of Your Information
We use your information for a variety of business and commercial purposes, including, personal information:
Transactional Purposes: to provision the requested services and orders; to establish and update your account; and for other transactional purposes.
Customer service/communications: to provide you with a personalized shopping experience; for technical support to answer your inquiries; to provide product updates/recalls and similar purposes.
Marketing/Advertising: for marketing purposes, including to provide you with special offers, promotions, news, and newsletters; to contact you about products we think may interest you; to target advertisements to you; to administer contests, promotions, and other offers; and for other marketing, advertising, and promotional purposes. Our marketing communications with you may include communications via postal mail and email. We, and our service providers, also use your information to determine the success of our advertising campaigns, regardless of the marketing and advertising channel.
Administration: for administrative purposes, including to manage our inventory; to help us better understand how our customers access and use our Site, including the pages viewed, ad impressions clicked, or other Site activity; to maintain security and operability of our Site (including for debugging purposes); to provide reports to prospective partners, service providers, regulators, and others; to implement and maintain security, anti-piracy, fraud prevention, and other services designed to protect you and us; to enforce this Policy, our Terms of Use, and other policies.
Research and development/Analytical purposes: for research and development purposes, including to analyze trends, improve our Site, products, and customer experience; to understand what parts of our Site are most popular or to improve upon our Site; to understand our customer demographics; and for other research and analytical purposes.
Legal compliance: to comply with applicable legal or regulatory obligations, including to respond to a subpoena or court order; to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations; and as part of legal proceedings.
Protection of us and others: where we believe it is necessary to protect us and others, including, without limitation to detect, prevent, and respond to fraud, security incidents, or other issues where we believe it is appropriate to protect us and others.
Additional Note Regarding Aggregated and Deidentified Data: We may use data in aggregated and deidentified form for research, analytics, marketing, and any other purposes.
Sharing of Information
We share your information, including personal information, with the following entities:
Corporate Relatives. We may share your information with any current or future parent company, affiliate, subsidiary or division.
Service Providers. We share your information with our service providers or others who perform functions on our behalf. For example, we share your information with service providers who host our Site, coordinate mailings, analyze aggregate information about our customers, assist us in detecting and deterring fraud, security incidents, or other unlawful activity, and for other business purposes as described above in how we use your information. We also permit service providers to collect information about you online through cookies and other tracking tools; please see Cookies and Tracking and Analytics Providers/Advertisers sections below. As part of our commitment to quality customer service, occasional communications may be sent on behalf of The Honest Kitchen, by an independent ratings and review service provider. Active, regular customers’ email addresses will be used by this service one time only, for the express purpose of independently evaluating our processes, including The Honest Kitchen’s general service, courtesy, selling, and shipping of actual orders placed, and will not be owned, shared or used for any other purpose by the service provider.
Carefully Selected Partners. If you choose to enter a joint promotion, then we may share your contact information (and other information that you provide to us in connection with that promotion) with the other party. The promotions may be subject to an additional or different privacy notice.
Site Users. We may share your information with other users of our Site. For example, if you post a review, a True Story, pictures, or other content on our Site, the contents of your post (including any pictures that you post) as well as other information may be available to all visitors to our Site.
Analytics Providers/Advertisers. As set forth above, we share information with analytics providers and advertisers to assist us in implementing and evaluating relevant advertising. Often the information that we share is collected from you through cookies and other tracking technologies set forth on our Sites and Apps. We also may disclose certain information (such as your email address) to Facebook Custom Audience, which may use it to target advertising to you. See Opt-out of Interest Based Advertising below.
Internet Service Providers/Operating Systems and Platforms: We may share your information with ISPs and operating systems to assist us in managing your preferences.
We may also share your information in the following ways:
Business Transfers. We may share your information with another entity if we or any of our current or future corporate relatives are acquired by or merged with another legal entity, if substantially all of our assets or the assets of one of our corporate relatives are sold or transferred to another legal entity, as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, or as part of a sale of a business or a similar transfer of assets.
In Response to Legal Process. We share your information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law or a regulatory requirement; to comply with governmental, administrative, or judicial process or other similar requirement or order, such as a subpoena or court order; to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations (without necessarily requiring the law enforcement or government agency requesting the information to formally serve us with a subpoena); or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved. We also reserve the right to report to appropriate law enforcement or governmental agencies any activities that we believe are in violation of applicable laws, rules, or regulations without providing notice.
To Protect Us and Others. We share your information where we believe it is necessary to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce a contract; to protect the legal rights, Site, or safety of you, The Honest Kitchen; its corporate relatives, and their respective employees, clients, partners, agents, other users, or the public in general; to enforce our Terms of Use or this Policy; and to monitor and remediate security issues.
Aggregate and De-Identified Information. We may disclose aggregate and de-identified information about our customers for marketing, advertising, research, or other purposes.
Opting-Out
If you receive communications from us that you do not want to receive, you can opt-out from receiving these communications by specifically telling us to stop sending them to you. To opt out of any email marketing, click the unsubscribe button at the bottom of the email. If you have opted in to receive text alerts, you may discontinue receiving these SMS offers by sending the SMS message “STOP” to the applicable short code.
You may also “opt-out” entirely from providing personal information to us by not registering on our Site.
Security
For your security, account access on our Site may be encrypted with Secure Sockets Layer Protocol (“SSL”) technology on both the client and server end by selecting the secure server option when prompted to do so. We take commercially reasonable measures designed to safeguard your data. Please note, however, that no measure is 100% perfect, and we recommend that you take measures to protect your data, such as not using the same password for multiple accounts, creating unique passwords, and safeguarding your own information. When you have finished using the Site, you should log off and exit your browser so no unauthorized persons can use our Site with your name and account information. Furthermore, if you provide any information to parties who operate web sites that are linked to or from our Web Site, different rules may apply to their collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of such other sites before revealing any sensitive or personal information. Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the ultimate security of any information you transmit.
Please note that e-mail may not be encrypted and cannot be considered a secure means of transmitting information. We do not ask you to submit your financial data, such as your credit card account numbers, via e-mail.
Cookies and Tracking
We and our service providers use cookies and other mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site. We do not typically associate this information with the personal information that we collect about you nor do we attempt to identify you as a natural person through this information.
• Cookies. We or our service providers may use cookies to track visitor activity on our Site. A cookie is a text file that a website transfers to your device for record-keeping purposes. We or our service providers may use cookies to track user activities on our Site, such as the web pages you view and time you spend on our services. The help section on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies may not be able to browse certain areas of the services. When you register at the Site, we may use a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We may use this ID to identify you (not by name but through the ID) in our database and to track information while you are on our Site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Site. Cookies also enable you to enter the Site as a registered user without having to log on each time.
• Clear GIFs, Pixel Tags and Other Technologies. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in functionality to cookies, which are embedded invisibly on web pages. We or our service providers may use clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs, pixel tags, or action tags, among other names), in connection with our services to perform functions like tracking the activities of visitors to our services, helping us manage content, and compiling statistics about usage of our Services. We or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in emails to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded.
• Embedded Scripts. We may use embedded scripts, which is code designed to collect information about how visitors interact with a website, such as the website which linked them to our Site.
• Analytics. We use service providers, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate the use of our Site. We or our service providers use automated devices and applications to evaluate use of services. We use these tools to help us improve our services, performance, and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies, such as web beacons or local storage objects (LSOs), to perform their services. To learn more about Google’s privacy practices, please review the Google Privacy Policy at https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. You can also download the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
• Do Not Track. Our Services do not respond to Do Not Track signals. You may disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies).
Interest-Based Advertising
We use service providers such as Google’s AdSense and AdWords to help us provide advertisements to you that are tailored to you based on interests that you have expressed on our Site or elsewhere (“Interest-Based Ads”). Any advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this Site. Any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google's own privacy policies. You may decide to disable Google cookies by clicking on: www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en. You can use Ads Settings to manage the Google ads you see and opt out of interest-based ads delivered by Google. You also may opt out of receiving Interest-Based Ads from many third-party ad networks, such as those provided by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding Interest-Based Ads by NAI members and DAA members, including how to opt out of Interest-Based Ads provided by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: optout.networkadvertising.org and optout.aboutads.info. Please note that opting out of participating ad networks does not mean that you will not see advertisements at all and you will continue to receive advertisements on other websites and from companies that do not participate in the above programs. Even if you opt out of interest-based ads, you may still see ads based on factors such as your general location derived from your IP address, your browser type and recent, previous searches related to your current search.
We also use Facebook advertising, including Facebook Custom Audience. As set forth above and in the Cookies and Tracking section below, we may disclose certain information (such as your email address) to Facebook Custom Audiences (for more information on Facebook Custom Audience click here ) so that we can better target ads and content to you and others with similar interests on third parties’ websites or media (“Custom Audiences”). We may also work with other ad networks and marketing platforms that enable us and other participants to target ads to Custom Audiences submitted by us and others. You may also control how Facebook and other third parties display certain ads to you, as explained further in their respective privacy policies or by using the opt-outs described in this paragraph.
Please note that even if you opt out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still send you communications about your account or any products or services you have purchased from us and we will still respond to your inquiries and requests for information.
Children's Privacy
We are concerned about the safety of children and their use of the Internet. This Site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 13. If we receive actual knowledge that we have received such personal information without the required verifiable parental consent, we will delete the information from our database as soon as we practicably can.
Effective Date and Future Changes
This Policy is effective as of March 2013. We may occasionally change this Privacy Policy. If we do, we will post the changes on the Site and the changes will take effect as soon as posted. If we change our information practices in the future, we will post the changes to our Site. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Site periodically.
Contact Information
Please read this Policy carefully and feel free to contact us by sending us a message by clicking here. You can also contact us by telephone at (866) 437-9729 if you have any inquiries, complaints or questions regarding its contents.
Additional Information for California Residents
In this section, we provide additional information to California residents about how we handle their personal information, as required under California privacy laws including the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”). This section does not address or apply to our handling of publicly available information lawfully made available by state or federal government records or other personal information that is exempt under the CCPA.
A. Categories of Personal Information Under the CCPA (Last Updated: July 1, 2020)
In this section we describe, generally, how we have collected and disclosed personal information about consumers in the prior 12 months (from the Last Updated data above).
Categories of Personal Information Collected and Disclosed. The table below identifies the categories of personal information (as defined by the CCPA) we have collected about consumers, as well as how we have disclosed such information for a business or commercial purpose. For more information about the business and commercial purposes for which we collect, use and disclose personal information, please see the Our Use of Your Information and the Sharing of Information sections above.
Personal Information Collected
Do We Disclose this Information?
Categories of Third Parties to Whom We May Disclose this Information
Categories
Description
1. Identifiers
Includes direct identifiers, such as name, alias user ID, username, account number or unique personal identifier; email address, phone number, address and other contact information; IP address and other online identifiers
YES
•   service providers
•   advisors and agents
•   government entities and law enforcement
•   affiliates and subsidiaries
•   advertising networks
•   data analytics providers
•   social networks
•   internet service providers
•   operating systems and platforms
2. Customer Records
Includes personal information, such as name, account name, user ID, contact information,  account number, and financial or payment information), that individuals provide us in order to purchase or obtain our products and services. For example, this may include information collected when an individual register for an account, purchases or orders our products and services
YES
•   service providers
•   advisors and agents
•   government entities and law enforcement
•   affiliates and subsidiaries
•   advertising networks
•   data analytics providers
•   social networks
•   internet service providers
•   operating systems and platforms
3. Commercial Information
Includes products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or use histories or tendencies.
YES
•   service providers
•   advisors and agents
•   government entities and law enforcement
•   affiliates and subsidiaries
•   advertising networks
•   data analytics providers
•   social networks
•   internet service providers
•   operating systems and platforms
4. Usage Data
Includes browsing history, clickstream data, search history, access logs and other usage data and information regarding an individual’s interaction with our websites and other services, and our marketing emails and online ads.
YES
•   service providers
•   advisors and agents
•   government entities and law enforcement
•   affiliates and subsidiaries
•   advertising networks
•   data analytics providers
•   social networks
•   internet service providers
•   operating systems and platforms
5. Inferences
Includes inferences drawn from other personal information that we collect to create a profile reflecting an individual’s preferences, characteristics, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities or aptitudes. [For example, we may analyze personal information in order to identify the offers and information that may be most relevant to customers, so that we can better reach them with relevant offers and ads.]
YES
•   service providers
•   advisors and agents
•   government entities and law enforcement
•   our affiliates and subsidiaries
•   advertising networks
•   data analytics providers
•   social networks
•   internet service providers
•   operating systems and platforms
Do We “Sell” Personal Information?
Under the CCPA, a “sale” includes disclosing or making available personal information to a third-party in exchange for monetary compensation or other benefits or value. Although we do not disclose personal information to third parties in exchange for monetary compensation, we may disclose or make available certain categories of personal information to third parties in order to receive certain benefits or services, such as when we make browsing information available to third party ad companies (through third party tags on our Site) in order to improve and measure our ad campaigns and reach users with more relevant ads and content. As defined by the CCPA, we may “sell” certain categories of personal information as follows:
• Usage Data and Identifiers to advertising networks and data analytics providers
• Customer Records to advertising networks and data analytics providers
Please also note that if we are engaged in a corporate transaction, we may disclose your information as part of that transaction. The CCPA does not consider such disclosure to be a sale.
Sources of Personal Information. As further described in the discussion about the Information We Collect About You, we may collect personal information from the following sources : directly from you; advertising networks; data analytics providers; social networks; internet service providers; operating systems and platforms; your friends; and government entities.
B. California Residents’ Rights
CCPA Rights. In general, California residents have the following rights with respect to their personal information:
1. Do-not-sell (opt-out): to opt-out of our sale of their personal information. While we may “sell” personal information as defined by the CCPA (although we do not sell information for any monetary compensation), we do not sell personal information about California consumers who we know are younger than 16 years old. California residents may opt out of sales of their personal information by us, by using our preference manager to opt out of “sales” via third party tags and cookies on our Sites. Please disable all optional cookies in
our Cookie Preference center here>
2. Right of deletion: to request deletion of their personal information that we have collected about them and to have such personal information deleted (without charge), subject to certain exceptions.
3. Right to know: with respect to the personal information we have collected about them in the prior 12 months, to require that we disclose the following to them (up to twice per year and subject to certain exemptions):
• categories of personal information collected;
• categories of sources of personal information;
• categories of personal information about them we have disclosed for a business purpose or sold;
• categories of third parties to whom we have sold or disclosed for a business purpose their personal information;
• the business or commercial purposes for collecting or selling their personal information; and
• a copy of the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about them.
4. Right to non-discrimination: the right not to be subject to discriminatory treatment for exercising their rights under the CCPA.
Submitting CCPA Requests. California residents may submit CCPA requests [to opt out of sales, requests to know (access) and requests to delete their personal information] through our privacy form here >
In addition, California residents may opt of “sales” of their personal information by us by [using our preference manager to opt out of “sales” via third party tags and cookies on our Sites.
When you submit a request to know or a request to delete, we will take steps to verify your request by matching the information provided by you with the information we have in our records. You must complete all required fields on our webform to verify your request. In some cases, we may request additional information in order to verify your request or where necessary to process your request. If we are unable to adequately verify a request, we will notify the requestor. Authorized agents may initiate a request on behalf of another individual online at the above link; authorized agents will be required to provide proof of their authorization and we may also require that the relevant consumer directly verify their identity and the authority of the authorized agent.
Financial Incentives. We may make available certain programs or offerings that are considered “financial incentives” under the CCPA. We do not currently offer any financial incentives.
For more information about our privacy practices, you may contact us as set forth in the [Contact Us] section above.
